And you call yourself human?!
Just What the [bleep] is yo' mama?
All right! Get ready!
Urya oi urya oi urya oi
That mole of yours, the
coloring is very light
Ro-man-ce
Ne, ne, ne, ne, necromancer!
That mole of yours, upon a closer look
has a single hair growing out of it
Ru ru ru ru rurururu!
I have a mole in the small of my back
Ro-man-ce
in the shape of the Big Dipper
Sei sei sei sei seiken koutai
My mole, compared to
others, is a bit large
Ji ji ji ji ji!
Oh-tsu,oi Oh-tsu, oi!
Right now, the two moles
Your mole, my mole
Oh-tsu,oi Oh-tsu, oi!
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)ﾀﾞﾒだ…
いまいち揃わねえな！
声も出てねえし…
こんなんことじゃ➡
Are joined together
12月のお通ちゃんのｺﾝｻｰﾄに
間に合わねえよ！
Wait a minute- wai, wai,
Wai, wai, wai, wai, Wait a minute-
お前らよぉ お通ちゃんが
全国区のｱｲﾄﾞﾙになったからって➡
Ah, and you still act like a human?
ちょっと ﾀﾙんでんじゃねえの？
Hoo hoo hoo hoo
Ah, well then, I'll say it clearly.
確かに お通ちゃんを
応援してるﾔﾂは➡
ｵﾚたち以外にも
もう たくさんいるよ｡
Hoo hoo hoo hoo
だが ｵﾚたちは 売れない時代から
彼女を支えてきた｡
Ah, that's enough already,
before I tear out that mole!
いわば 寺門 通という
でかい家の屋台骨だぜ｡
Buchi!
もっと こう
ﾌﾟﾗｲﾄﾞ持っていこうや！
And you call yourself human?
(親衛隊たち)お… おす！
What the [bleep] is yo' mama?!
特に軍曹！ ｵﾒｴ
幹部のくせに… って あれ？
Hey, more power! Where's that [bleep]?!
(幹部)あの…
あっちで ﾒｰﾙでござる｡
And you call yourself human?
なんか最近 女の子と
知り合いになったとかで➡
What the [bleep] is yo' mama?!
なにかっちゃあ ﾒｰﾙを…｡
And you call yourself human?
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)なんだと…？
軍曹のくせに ﾒﾙ友だと!?
What the [bleep] is yo' mama?!
わかってんのか！
ﾒｰﾙなんてものは悪魔の道具だ！
No good. You're not in sync. And
what happened to your voices?
At this rate, we'll never be ready
for Otsu's December concert.
Are you listening?!
Maybe you've gotten lazy just because
Otsu's become a national idol?!
んなものは全部
ｳｿっぱちだ！ ﾃﾞﾀﾗﾒだ！
There's no doubt we're not the
only ones rooting for Otsu.
あの そういうんじゃなくて➡
なんか ﾌﾞﾛｸﾞとか
ﾆｸｼｨで知り合ったらしくて｡
But we've backed her up long
before she became popular.
ﾌﾞﾌﾞﾌﾞ… ﾌﾞﾛｸﾞだとぉ!?
We are the pillars of support
for Tsu Terakado!
あんな 毎日どこに行って
何食ったとか➡
誰それと ｹﾝｶしたとか
ｱｲﾂ ｳｻﾞくね？ とか➡
Let's put more pride into our routine!
明日 ﾃｽﾄでﾕｰｳﾂ みたいな
文章 垂れ流し場に➡
R-Right!
Especially you, sergeant!
You're an officer, yet... Huh?
親しげなｺﾒﾝﾄ書いて
ｺﾒﾝﾄ返してもらって➡
U-Umm... He's checking
his email over there.
仲よしですか 急接近ですか？
ありえねえんだよ！
Seems he met a girl.
あん？ どうなんよ！
ﾆｸｼｨだとぉ？
And they email each other
about everything.
奇跡のﾏｲﾆｸとか
気取ってんじゃねえだろうな？
What?! He's a sergeant and
he's emailing a friend?!
んなもん いくらでも
虚偽申請やれっじゃねえか！
どんだけ頭ん中 ｽｲｰﾂだよ あん？
Get this! Email is the devil's tool!
どうせ相手も修正ﾊﾞﾘﾊﾞﾘ
入りまくりの ﾌﾞｻｷｬﾗだろうが！
My boyfriend jilted me and I'm so lonely.
I could use some consoling.
そ… それがですね➡
Work is so hectic, my spirit has run dry.
Let's enjoy some good wine together.
もともとは お通ちゃんｺﾐｭで
知り合ったとかで➡
結構 かわいい子で➡
軍曹が 親衛隊の
幹部だって言ったら➡
Is it okay if I call you "Brother"?
すっげえ尊敬されちゃって➡
Lies, all of it! Bloody lies!
向こうから ﾏｲﾆｸ申請きたって…｡
ほら 今年 頭にﾘﾘｰｽした
『お前の姉ちゃん 出会い系』から➡
It's not like that. They met through
some blog or nixi and...
[Note: nixi is a parody of the Japanese
social networking site "mixi".]
女子人気が ぐわ～っ
上がったじゃないっすか！
B-B-Blog?!
今 ｷﾃるんっすよ！
えっ…？
Crap like, where and what
you do and eat every day;
(幹部)今日 このあと
言おうと思ってたんですけど➡
親衛隊にも女子部とか
作ってもいいんじゃないっすか？
you had an argument with so-and-so;
that guy is such a pest;
I dread tomorrow's test.
じょ… 女子部？
You write a comment and
you get a comment back.
(幹部)ｵﾚたち お通ちゃんには➡
世界的なｱｲﾄﾞﾙに
なってもらいたいんですよ！
Oh, you're friends? You're great chums?
老若男女あらゆる人から好かれる
ﾋﾟﾖﾝｾみたいな歌姫に！
Wrong!
Huh? Well?! nixi?!
お通ちゃんの幸せは
ｵﾚたちの幸せっす！
ってことは ｵﾚたちの幸せだって➡
Like it's a great miracle or something?!
お通ちゃんの幸せに
なるんじゃないっすか！
You can make any false
claim you want on it!
ｵﾚたちの幸せは お通ちゃんの…｡
(軍曹)ｷﾞｬ～ｯ！
Just how naive are you anyway?!
And the girl's probably some ugly hoe whose
picture has been totally retouched.
(軍曹)た… 隊長！
W-Well...
(新八)軍曹！
They first met through an Otsu-chan
forum and she's really cute.
寺門 通 親衛隊隊規
二十三条を言ってみろぉ！
ｲﾀﾀ… た… 隊員は みだりに
婦女子と密通することなかれ！
He told her that he was a
sergeant in the Fan Club,
and she was so impressed and she's
the one who started to chat with him.
この禁 犯したものは
ｽﾊﾟｲとみなす であります！
Hey! Ever since she released the song,
そのとおりだ 軍曹！
"Your Sister's On A Dating Website," her popularity
with women has skyrocketed, remember?
ｷｻﾏは幹部でありながら
この隊規に違反した！
よって 鼻ﾌｯｸﾃﾞｽﾄﾛｲﾔｰ
ﾌｧｲﾅﾙﾄﾞﾘｰﾑの刑に処す！
Huh?
We meant to bring it up later,
but maybe we can have a
girl's division of Fan Club?
G-Girl's division?
We want Otsu to gain worldwide fame.
おい！
(隊員)ひぃ！
A song princess like Beyonce
loved by everyone,
young and old, male and female!
Our happiness is Otsu's happiness.
はい…｡
お前らのｹｰﾀｲも見せろ｡
Doesn't that mean, her happiness
is our happiness?!
やってませんよ！ ﾎﾞｸらは
女とﾒｰﾙなんてしてませんよ｡
Our happiness is Otsu-chan's?
つうか ｹｰﾀｲなんて いらねえし！
ｵﾚも いらねえよ こんなもん！
(隊員)女とﾒｰﾙなんて
するわけないっすよ！
(隊員)ｵﾚのｹｰﾀｲ 壊れてるし｡
(隊員)こんなの いらねえ！
C-Captain!
Sergeant! Recite Article 23 of the
Tsu Terakado Fan Club Bylaws!
そうだ！ 女とﾒｰﾙして
ﾍﾗﾍﾗしてんじゃねえぞ ｺﾗ!!
全然うらやましくも
なんともないね！
Owwww! It says, "Secret communication
with women is forbidden!
(隊員たち)おうよ！
なにがﾒｰﾙだ 文通だ！
Anyone breaking this rule will
be deemed a spy." Sir!
そんな軟弱なﾏﾈしてんじゃねえ！
(隊員たち)おうよ！
Correct! Sergeant, you are an officer.
男だったら… 男だったら➡
己の体でぶつかって
愛を伝えろ！
Yet you broke this rule!
(隊員たち)おぉ～!!
お通ちゃ～ん 好きだぁ!!
Thus...!
You are sentenced to
the Nose Hook Destroyer Final Dream!
そうだ それが男だ！
文字なんかで 思いが伝わるか！
直接 言葉で伝えてこそ！
文通なんて ｸｿくらえ…！
ん？
Hey!
なんだ これ？
波に流されてきたのか｡
[Do you want to delete the selected messages?]
[Yes  No]
なんか入ってる｡
Yes...
Show me all your cell phones.
I-I don't... We don't email girls.
A-And I don't need a cell phone.
Y-Yeah! Who needs this thing!
I wouldn't email a girl!
｢私と文通してくれませんか？｣
Besides, my cell phone is broken!
I don't need this!
Right! Quit emailing girls
and acting like wimps!
ぶ ぶ… 文通なんて
文通なんて…｡
We're not jealous of anything
like that, right?!
Right!
ｸ… ｸｿありがとうございました！
Who cares about emails! Correspondence!
Quit acting so soft!
Right!
If you're men... if you're men...
beat your own chests and
declare your love!
Right!
Otsu-chan! We love you!
That's right. That's being men!
The written word cannot
convey our feelings!
Say it directly! Out loud!
Written messages are crap!
What's this?
Did it wash up with the waves?
There's something inside.
Do you believe in destiny? I do.
After all, you're reading
this now, aren't you?
Will you correspond with me?
Correspond... Correspond...
Damn it! Thank you! Thank you so much!
[Note: Parody of Sanji's line to "Red
Foot" Zeff in ONE PIECE.]
[To whom it may concern: We're sorry
about the week before last week.]
[All told, we're starting second half
of GinTama Anime 3rd yearrrrr!!]
["Some Things Can Only Be Conveyed
Through the Written Word"]
(銀時)あ？
新八の様子がおかしい？
Huh? Shinpachi is acting funny?
Shinpachi always acts weird, Sis.
(神楽)新八なんて
いつもおかしいｱﾙよ 姉御｡
I know, but it's more than usual.
(お妙)それは そうなんだけど
いつにも増してっていうか➡
最近は 家に帰ってきても➡
Lately, he comes home and goes straight
to his room. And he hardly talks.
すぐに 部屋に こもってしまって
ろくに話もしないし｡
And he doesn't sleep 'til morning...and
seems intent on writing something?
それに 朝方まで寝ないで➡
部屋で なにか
ｼｺｼｺやっているようなんです｡
あっ ｼｺｼｺ？
そうなの｡
Intent on writing?
Yes. There are crumpled
balls of paper on the floor
部屋の前に
丸めた紙が散乱してて➡
いったい何をしているのかしら？
and I just don't know what he's doing.
(お妙)夜な夜な
何を ｼｺｼｺやっているのかしら？
What is he writing so late at night?
とにかく 難しい年頃だから➡
Anyway, he's at a difficult age.
こういうことは 男の銀さんに
聞いたほうがいいかと思って｡
And I think a man like you
should speak to him, Gin-san.
(お妙)ちょっと
様子を見てきてもらえます？
Can you go see what's up with him?
ほっとけよ 男はな➡
Just leave him alone.
When boys get to a certain age,
family becomes a bother.
年頃になると 家族とか
鬱陶しくなる時期があんだよ｡
そうやって 自立していくの｡
That's how they become independent.
Independent? Shinpachi, independent?
(神楽)自立？
新八のくせに自立ｱﾙか？
あんな 生まれたての馬より
よろっちいくせに｡
He's more helpless than a colt at birth.
そうなのよ｡
まぁ 自立はいいけど➡
She's right. Becoming
independent is fine.
いったい 部屋で
何を ｼｺｼｺやっているのかしら？
But what is he doing cooped
up in his room?
それも 自立に必要なのかしら？
Is that necessary in becoming
self-reliant?
By independent, I mean... Standing up.
自立っていうか…｡
まぁ たってるよ
１人で ある意味｡
Being alone and well...
要するによ… あっ｡
ん？
ん～ んん！
う～ん…
何と書き出せばいいんだ？
Hmm... How should I start this?
氏も素性も知れない人に
手紙を出すなんて｡
Writing a letter to a total stranger...
ﾎﾝﾄに 何も知らないもんな｡
I don't know anything about her.
わかってるのは…｡
All I do know is...
((運命って信じますか？))
Do you believe in destiny?
Heh...
信じる！ 断固 信じるよ｡
Yes, I do! I really believe in
it! Yes, that's how I'll start.
そうだ この書き出しにしよ｡
≪新八｡
Shinpachi.
うわぁ～ はい！ 銀さん!?
来てたんですか？
Yes! Gin-san! You're here?!
お前よ あんま 姉ちゃんに
心配かけんじゃねえぞ｡
Hey, don't worry about
your sister too much.
え… 何 言ってんですか？
それと もうひとつ｡
Huh? What're you saying?
One more thing
手は きちんと洗えよ｡
make sure you wash your hands.
何を気持わりい気まわしてんだ！
Get your mind out of the gutter!
何 勘違いしてんですか！
違いますからね！
What are you thinking? You're totally
mistaken. I'm not like that!
ﾎﾞｸ そういうんじゃ
ないですからね！
っつうか なんで いつもより
ちょっと優しくなってんだよ!?
And why're you acting nicer than
usual? It gives me the creeps!
気持わりいんだよ！
え？ 違うの？
Huh?! You're not?
こういうんじゃないの？
You're not into this stuff?
なんだよ｡
ｵﾚは てっきりｱﾚかと思ってよ…｡
Oh man, I was wrong. Absolutely wrong.
完全に勘違いしてたわ｡
悪いな わざわざ来てもらったのに
はい 解散！
Sorry you had to come for
nothing. You can go.
ｱﾝﾀら ﾎﾞｸが部屋で いったい
何してると思ってたんですか!?
Hey! What's the big idea?
誰だよ ｿｲﾂら!?
どっから連れてきたんだよ！
What did you think I was
doing in my room?!
Where'd you find them anyway?!
おい これ忘れてんぞ！
Hey, you forgot this!
使う？
何にだよ！
Wanna use it?
For what?!
ｱﾈｺﾞ 何を茹でてるｱﾙか？
Sis, what are you boiling?
(お妙)
なんでもないのよ 神楽ちゃん｡
It's nothing, Kagura.
Writing? Then you've been
writing letters at night?
文通？ ﾊｧ？
じゃあ お前
夜な夜な書いてたのって手紙？
ﾎﾝﾄ 青くせぇこと やってんな｡
Man, you're such a kid.
姉上には言わないでくださいよ｡
Please don't tell my sister.
女の子と文通なんて知ったら
いろいろと ｱﾚなんで…｡
If she finds out I'm writing letters to
a girl, it would be uncomfortable.
｢ｱﾚなんで｣って何だよ？
Uncomfortable? Why? Are you thinking
of doing something bad?
何か やらしいことでも
考えてんのか？
か… 考えてねえよ！
No way! That's exactly the kind
of conclusion I don't want.
そういうふうに思われるのが
ｲﾔなんだよ！
ﾎﾞｸは ただ純粋な気持で
彼女と交流したいだけです｡
I want to know her on
a purely platonic level.
交流って何を交わらせるんだよ？
友情ですよ 友情！
Know her how?
It's friendship! Friendship!
少年は友情 努力
勝利で できてるんですから！
Youth is all about friendship,
perseverance, victory!
考えてみてくださいよ｡
I mean, think about it.
あの広大な海を漂って
ﾎﾞｸに届いた手紙ですよ？
It crossed the vast ocean and reached
me! It must be destiny.
何かの縁があるんですよ｡
But if Sis finds out about it, she'll
say I lack morals and get angry.
でも 姉上が知ったら➡
ふしだらとか
怒られるに決まってますもん｡
That's not true.
んなことねえよ｡
Your sister is pretty understanding
about things like that.
意外と そういうのは
理解あるんじゃねえの？
お前の姉ちゃん｡
いや ないですよ｡
No, she's not.
Shin-chan.
(お妙)新ちゃん？
姉上!?
Sister?!
お茶とお菓子 持ってきたから
よかったら食べて｡
I brought some tea and
sweets, so have some.
はい｡
Here...
え…？
Just in case, it's not enough.
た… 足りないと
いけないと思って…｡
これ 糸ｺﾝﾆｬｸ｡
This is...stringy konjac root.
えっ!?
新ちゃん｡
Huh?
Shin-chan... Shin-chan... No matter what you do,
you'll always be my little brother.
新ちゃんは どんなになっても
私の弟だから…｡
あっ…｡
You see? She's very understanding.
ほらな わかってくれてるだろ？
どんな理解のされ方してんだ!?
What the hell is she thinking?!
Just what did you tell my sister?!
ｱﾝﾀ 人の姉ちゃんに
何 話したんだ？
なんで
お茶として ﾛｰｼｮﾝ出てくんだよ!?
What's this lotion doing with the tea?!
なんで ｺﾝﾆｬｸに穴あいてんだよ!?
完全に勘違いしてるよ！
And why does this konjac
root have a hole in it?!
She has it totally wrong!
１回も
目 合わせてくんなかったよ！
And she didn't look me
in the eye! Not once!
どうしてくれんだ！
これから超 気まずいだろうが!!
How're you gonna fix this?!
How can we face each other now?!
Now, now. Calm down.
まぁまぁ 落ち着けよ｡
ﾛｰｼｮﾝがｱﾘってことは
文通もｱﾘだろ｡
She gave you lotion.
That means you'll have time in private,
to write. I'd say that's great.
よかったじゃん｡
全然よくねえんだよ！
It's not great! I'd rather have
her find out about the letters!
文通ﾊﾞﾚたほうが
はるかにﾏｼだったわ！
This has such a grown-up taste.
大人の味ｱﾙな～｡
おかわりなら
いくらでもあるから｡
There's lots more if you want seconds.
And? Just what did you write
anyway? Let's see.
で 結局 何て書いたんだよ？
手紙｡
見せてみろよ｡ 貸してみろ｡
Never mind! Stop!
いいですよ！
ちょっと やめてください！
｢はじめまして｡ 手紙 読みました｡
"How do you do? I read your
letter. Isn't it strange?
とっても不思議なことですね｡
It crossed a vast ocean and reached me"
こんな広い海を渡って
ﾎﾞｸの元に届いたなんて｣｡
おいおい なんだよ これ？
Hey, this is it?! It's too
long and so ordinary.
長えし おもしろくねえし
普通だし｡
別に いいでしょ！
So what?! What's the use of putting
on a pretense? It's a letter.
奇をてらったって
しかたないでしょ 手紙で！
お前 この子と
仲よくなりたいんでしょ？
You want to get to know this girl, right?
お近づきになりたいんでしょ？
You want to get close to her, right?
You have to show off.
奇をてらわないで どうすんだよ！
え？ てらうって…｡
Huh? Show off?
Look, she tossed her letter-in-a-bottle
into the ocean
相手は 手紙を海に流して
ﾗﾝﾀﾞﾑで 文通相手 探すような➡
hoping to find a random pen-pal.
How much more showy can you get?
奇のてらい方をしてるんだよ｡
And this brief message.
しかも この簡潔な文章！
奇抜なことが好きなﾔﾂってのはな
飽き性が多いんだ｡
Unconventional women like
her get bored quickly.
おそらく
３行以上の文章は読まねえよ｡
She won't read more than
three sentences.
確かに ﾎﾞｸの手紙は 長いうえに
要点が よくわからないですね｡
I guess my letter is too long
and doesn't get to the point.
向こうの情報が ろくにない以上➡
Since you don't know anything about her,
こっちのことを
わかってもらうしかないだろ｡
you need to say something
about yourself.
And you can introduce yourself
in three sentences.
自己紹介なら ３行で収まる｡
And add a photo, just like she did.
あと 写真もだ｡ 向こうに合わせて
こっちも 写真 送らねえと｡
I see, I guess so.
そうか… そういや そうだ｡
でも 自己紹介なんて
たったの３行でできますか？
But can I really introduce myself
in only three sentences?
できるだろ｡ とにかく
ｼﾝﾌﾟﾙに わかりやすくしねえとよ｡
Sure you can. Just keep it simple
and easy to understand.
こんなん どうだ？
How's this?
[Shinpachi Shimura]
[I changed my glasses.]
That tankobon?!
なんの
単行本だ！
This is the back cover of a graphic
novel! I've seen it before!
これ 単行本の表紙の裏の
あれだろ これ！
よく 見たことあるわ｡ なんで
著者近影 眼鏡しかねえんだよ！
Why is the writer's most recent photogragh
only of his glasses?!
Because if the writer reveals himself,
it lowers the value of his work.
著者は 姿 見せると 作品の人気が
下がる場合があるからな｡
前は ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣も 新年号じゃ➡
In the past, JUMP would include photos
作家先生の集合写真とか
載っけてたんだよ｡
of the creators in their New Year's issue.
But somewhere along the
way, it stopped, right?
いつの間にか なくなっただろ？
つまり そういうことだよ｡
And that's the reason why.
Don't be so rude!! And not only that,
失礼なこと 言うんじゃねえよ！
つうか 文章
３行どころか➡
there's only one sentence, not three.
１行しか
ないでしょうが｡
写真も文章も
眼鏡にしか➡
And the photo and the sentence
only focuses on my glasses.
ふれてねえよ！
Well, I thought about what to write,
いろいろ 書こうと
思ったんだけどな｡
but there were only your glasses
that were out of the ordinary.
眼鏡しかなかったんだよ 凹凸が｡
凹凸って なんだ！
Out of the ordinary?!
ほら… お前って 平面に 眼鏡だけ
転がったような人間じゃん｡
You know, you're sort of a flat person
with only those glasses that stand out.
できるだけ 引き延ばしたけど
これが 限界だな｡
I tried to bring that out somehow,
but this is the limit.
Am I such a sorry human being?!
どんだけ つまらねえ人間だよ！
いや でも これくらいのほうが
想像の余地があって➡
No, it's actually better since there's
lots of room for imagination.
It conveys something deeper,
something more fashionable.
深い感じになるんだよ｡
ｵｼｬﾚな感じに｡
どこが深いんだよ！
眼鏡 買った報告しかしてねえよ｡
What's deep about only saying
that I've changed glasses?!
つうか 買ってないからね
眼鏡なんて｡
And besides, I haven't
bought new glasses.
わかった！ じゃあ こうしよう｡
All right, then how about this?
深みが一気に増しただろ？
[I changed. My glasses. You know.
-Shinpachi Shimura]
Much more substance, right? And
there are the three sentences.
３行に
なったし｡
You just broke it up!
みつを風になっただけだろうが！
There's not even a millimeter
more in substance!
１ﾐﾘたりとも 深さ 増してねえよ｡
All it says is that I bought new glasses.
眼鏡 買っただけだからね！
And let me repeat again, I haven't
bought new glasses!
つうか 何度も言うけど
買ってないからね 眼鏡！
In order to make it interesting,
a little fabrication is necessary.
話を おもしろくするためには
多少の捏造は必要なんだよ｡
On television, that type of thing could get
you kicked out of the TV federation!
ﾃﾚﾋﾞで それ やると
連盟から はずされるから！
Only someone clueless to the
situation would say that.
それは 現場を知らねえﾔﾂの
言うことだろ｡
A little acting is necessary here.
少しくらい 演出つけるのも
必要なんだって｡
Well, this letter is not interesting at all!
まったく
おもしろくなってないから！
どうせなら
もっと 鮮やかな演出してよ！
If you're gonna make a production
out of it, add a little polish!
３行です｡
Three sentences!
やっぱり 最低３行 たっぷり
使わないと きついですって｡
To make an impact, there's gotta
be at least three sentences.
３行ね…｡
まぁ なんとか やってみるか｡
Three sentences, huh? Well, I'll try.
これなんて どうだ？
[Thank you for sending me so many glasses.
I will wear them along with the S.]
How's this?
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣の目次ｺﾒﾝﾄに
なってんだろうが！
That's like an insert in the Table
of Contents in JUMP!
It's straight from the magazine!
まんま 目次ｺﾒﾝﾄだろうが！
Why's it like a Valentine's greeting?
なんで
ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝみたくなってんだよ！
なんで たくさんの眼鏡が
送られてきてんだよ！
What's this about "so
many glasses"?!
このＳって… ｽﾀｯﾌって 誰だ!?
ｽﾀｯﾌじゃねえ｡ 新八のＳだ｡
And this "S"?! What "Staff"?!
That doesn't mean staff. It stands
for S as in Shinpachi.
Shut up! Only Shinpachi wears glasses!
Nothing's been changed!
うっせえよ！ 結局 新八しか
眼鏡かけてねえだろうが!!
It's completely off the mark.
なんにも 状況打破できてねえよ！
つうか 完全に
主旨 ずれてるでしょ｡
If I send this, she wouldn't
think it's a letter to her,
こんなもん 送ったら
あの子から 手紙じゃなくて➡
but rather an acknowledgment
that I received glasses.
眼鏡 受け取ったみたいに
なってるでしょ これ｡
いったん
原点に立ち返りましょうよ｡
Let's just start over.
From the very beginning.
振り出しから やり直しましょう｡
そうか！ そうだな｡
Oh, I guess you're right.
原点だよ 新八｡
お前の言うとおりだ｡
From the start, Shinpachi.
Just as you said, go back to the
beginning and think it over.
最初に戻って考えればいいんだよ｡
はぁ？
思い出してみろ 新八｡
Think back, Shinpachi.
お前は この手紙の
いったい どこに惹かれたか｡
What is it about this letter
that captured you?
Yes. It's not the unconventional way
it was sent nor the brief message.
そう それは
奇抜な手紙の送り方でも➡
簡潔な文章でもない｡ これだろ？
Wasn't it this?
うっ！ ち… 違います!!
N-No! I don't judge people by their looks.
ﾎﾞｸは そんな 人を見た目で判断…｡
は～い じゃあ 聞きますが➡
Well then, let me ask you.
If this girl happened to be ugly,
would you think about replying?
あなたは
もし この子が ﾌﾞｻｲｸだったら➡
文通しようと思いましたか？
うっ…｡
Uh...
そう つまり いくら 頭 悩ませて
名文 作ろうが 何しようが➡
So you see?
No matter how hard you wrack your brains
to come up with the perfect lines,
結局 最後にものをいうのは…｡
ultimately what counts is...
見た目なんだよ｡
What you see!
否定できない…｡
I can't argue with that.
But, if that's so, a loser like
me hasn't got a chance.
いや しかし だとすれば
こんな冴えないﾎﾞｸに 勝ち目は…｡
Shinpachi, take off your glasses.
新八 眼鏡を取れ｡
ﾑ… ﾑﾀﾞですよ｡
It's no use. Even if I take
off my glasses, I...
眼鏡なんか取ったって
ﾎﾞｸなんか…｡
新八 健全な魂ってのはな
表にもあらわれるもんだ｡
Shinpachi, a healthy soul manifests
itself on one's exterior too.
…魂｡
Soul?
安心しろ
お前は いいもんもってる｡
Take heart. You have a good soul.
銀さん…｡
Gin-san...
やります ﾎﾞｸ やってみます！
I will! I'll do it!
♪♪～
どうですか こういう感じで!?
What do you think of
something like this?!
Hey, that's good. Yes, yes, yes, yes!
おぉ～ いいね いいね～！
ｲｴｽ ｲｴｽ ｲｴｽ…！
A little more to the left.
もうちょい 左だなぁ～｡
はい 笑って～ 新八君！
Okay, smile, Shinpachi-kun.
Photograph me! Shinpachi-kun is right here!
ﾎﾞｸを撮れよ！
新八君こっち～!!
Assault Buster!
ｱｻﾙﾄﾊﾞｽﾀｰ！
うっ うぅ…｡
You're wrong.
ち 違うだろ？
新八の成分の95％は 眼鏡だ｡
These glasses make up
95% of you, Shinpachi.
どっちかっつうと
もう こっちが新八だろ？
In fact, these are more Shinpachi than you.
５％しか
ﾎﾞｸの居場所ねえのかよ!?
You're saying I only make up 5%?!
Well, 3% is water, 2% is garbage.
残り３％が 水分で
２％が ｺﾞﾐだな｡
You're labelling me garbage?!
Or maybe, I'm not even 2%?
ｺﾞﾐの中に入ってんの!?
もしかして ２％ないの!?
[Shinpachi Shimura]
[I bought new glasses.]
つぅか これ さっきと
寸分 違わねえだろうが！
More importantly, this is exactly
the same as before!
違う意味で振り出しに
戻ってるだろ!!
Except the reasoning is different!
Yeah, but the ones hanging on this
tree are nice. It's got substance.
いやぁ でも この木にかかってる
１枚なんかは いいよなぁ｡
ｻﾏになってるよ～！
新八にかけろ～!!
Put them on me!
But there's just something missing.
だが いまいち
決定打に欠けるなぁ｡
あたりめえだろ！
本体ねえんだよ！
Damn right! They're not on me!
Isn't there a better scenario?
もっと
いいﾓﾁｰﾌは ねえかぁ～｡
あぁ これも違う～｡
あぁ あれも違う…｡
Not this. Not this either.
Which one is most like Shinpachi?!
新八の もっとも新八らしい
新八は どれだぁ!?
…おぉっ!!
All right! This is it!
よし これだぁ！
(沖田)近藤さん➡
Is Kondo-san here?
来てませんかね？
まったくの別人だろうがっ!!
That's a different person!!
They turned out pretty cool, Shinpachi.
かなり
かっこよく撮れたな 新八！
新八じゃねえよ それ！
何 死んでいい!?
That's not Shinpachi. What?
Should I just die?
♪♪～
Sister! Look! Look! Really!
(うらら)
お姉ちゃ～ん 大変 大変!!
ﾎﾝﾄに… ﾎﾝﾄに届いたよ！
お姉ちゃんの手紙！
It really came, a letter for you!
来たよ 手紙の返事！
You got a reply to your letter!
This can't be happening. Someone
really picked up the letter.
まさか…
ﾎﾝﾄに あの手紙を➡
拾ってくれる人がいたなんて…｡
(うらら)見せて 見せて！
Let me see! Let me see!!
What does it say, Sister?!
なんて書いてあるの？
お姉ちゃん！
｢手紙届きました｡
"I received your letter. I'm looking forward
to our correspondence from now on."
文通 これから
よろしくお願いします｡
ﾎﾞｸの名前は…｡
"My name is
志村 新八です｣｡
Shinpachi Shimura."
[To Be Continued]
[Preview]
My brother, Shinpachi-kun, is worried
about his relationship?!
Then this is where I, Kondo,
the Love Expert, come in!
Shut up, stalker!!
That's not happening.
Please come back and do your work.
All of you?!  How cruel!!
The next episode... "Sometimes
You Must Meet to Understand."
[Somehow, the Shinsengumi get involved
in Shinpachi's letter-writing lessons.]
[One misunderstanding leads to another. What
happens to Shinpachi's correspondence?]
あれ？ なんか まだ１分くらい
あまってるんですけど｡
Uh... it seems we still have
another minute left.
ｼｰｯ！ 黙ってろ 新八！
Shh! Stay quiet, Shinpachi!
(神楽)作戦ｱﾙ 作戦！
作戦？
We're on a mission here. A mission.
A mission?
先週 BGｵﾝﾘｰで延々放送したら
やっぱり偉い人に…｡
Last week, when they broadcasted the part
with one image and only audio.
I suspect, the big guys up there...
(神楽)｢全然 金かかって
ねえじゃねえか！
Yelled "You didn't spend any
money on this episode at all!
制作費削るぞ～！｣って
怒られたｱﾙ！
We'll lower your production budget!!"
まぁね…
確かに安くあがったよね｡
True, we were able to finish
the episode on the cheap.
But, think about it.
だが 考えてみろ？
For those episodes, the staff put in a lot
of effort and created more images.
今までｽﾀｯﾌが
がんばっちゃって➡
予算以上の枚数かけて作った
話数のｵｰﾊﾞｰぶんは➡
Costs went over-budget and
need to be paid immediately.
現場持ちで 赤字制作だ｡
We're actually losing money
creating those episodes.
It's not fair.
(神楽)不公平ｱﾙ！
まぁ しょうがないよね｡
Oh well, what can you do.
そこでだ 毎週 番組が
終わったと見せかけて➡
So! What if we show one
minute of background with
そのあとに
こうやってこっそり➡
only audio after the actual
episode every week.
BGｵﾝﾘｰを
１分づつまぜとくんだよ！
Then... hey, presto!
(神楽)すると あ～ら不思議！
In six months, we'd have one episode
worth of background art with only audio.
半年で１話分が
BGｵﾝﾘｰで出来上がるってわけだ！
Ooh, I see! That's even more pernicious!!
おぉ なるほど～！
って そのほうが悪質だろう！
やっぱり ﾀﾞﾒか…｡
I knew it wouldn't work.
(神楽)と 言ってる間に 時間ｱﾙ｡
And time's up as we speak.
[Unchanging and unapologetic.]
[The third season of the GinTama anime goes
in to its third year with high ratings!!]